skycig.co.uk 2014-10-24

# Privacy Policy - blu UK Electronic Cigarettes, E Cigarettes

Effective:01/05/2014

We at Cygnet UK Trading Limited, trading as "blu" (“we”, “us”, “our”) with registered office at 90 Fetter Lane, London EC4A 1EQ understand that your privacy is extremely important and we would like to thank you in advance for your trust. Your personal information is important to us as well. Our Privacy Policy, together with our Terms of Use (and any other documents referred to in these documents) cover personal information collection and use on our website www.blucigs.co.uk products and services (our "Site").

Cygnet UK Trading Limited has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your information. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [privacy@blucigs.co.uk](mailto:privacy@blucigs.co.uk). If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint). The TRUSTe certification only covers information collected on [www.blucigs.co.uk](http://www.blucigs.co.uk/). 

Please read the following carefully to understand our practices regarding your personal information and how we will treat it.

## Information We Collect and How We Use It

The personal information we gather from you includes:

  * Your full name and contact details (including your telephone number, fax number, email and postal addresses);
  * Details of transactions you carry out through our Site and the fulfilment of your orders;
  * Payment and purchase details when you purchase a product from us (including credit card number and expiration date);
  * If you contact us (via the Site or otherwise), we may keep a record of that correspondence.

Your personal information helps us with the handling of your orders (including sending you order notifications and reminders), delivering of products, payment processing, communicating information to you about the status of your order, products, services, occasional newsletters, promotional material and website updates including ensuring that content from our Site is presented in the most effective manner for you and your computer or device.

Your personal information helps us to improve our services to you, to prevent fraud or website abuse and enables our third party suppliers to follow through with logistics on our behalf. 

When you create a blu account or submit any personal information via telephone, correspondence, e-mail or fax, all information that is received is securely stored.

If you sign up for our affiliate program we require you to provide us with certain personal information (such as your name, email address, address, Tax ID, SSN, VAT, and phone number). We also require you to provide us with your PayPal account information if this is the way you choose to be paid. We use this information to create your affiliate account and to fund your account.

In some instances, for example if you choose to have items shipped to another person we will collect their name, phone number, email address and mailing address. We will use this information only to send the items that you have selected to have shipped to the selected individuals. This information will be stored within the address section of your blu account so that you may select it again for use in future orders. This information will also be stored within our order records so that we may have access to it should you have any problems with your order, such as non-receipt of goods. You should only provide us with information about other people if you have their permission to do so. 

## Social Media (Features) and Widgets

Our Site includes Social Media features, such as the _Facebook Like_ button and Widgets, such as the _Share this_ button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social Media features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

## Public Forums

Our Site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them.

## Customer Testimonials

We post customer testimonials on our Site which may contain personally identifiable information and a photo. We obtain our customers' consent expressly via the tick box on the web form used to submit the testimonial prior to posting the testimonial, photo and customer name on the Site.

## Cookies

Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser to make it easier to navigate our website, to help protect your information and to collect information required to make it easier for us to understand what products interest our community. The help menu on the menu bar of most browsers will inform you about how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, to notify you when you receive a new cookie and how to disable cookies. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any information you submit while on our site.

The use of cookies by third parties is not covered by our privacy policy. We do not have access or control over these cookies.

We use the following categories of cookies on our Site :

**Strictly Necessary Cookies**   
These cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around the Site and use its features. Without these cookies, services you have asked for such as remembering your login details or shopping basket items cannot be provided. 

**Performance Cookies**   
These cookies collect anonymous information on how people use our Site. For example, we use Google Analytics cookies to help us understand how customers arrive at our Site, browse or use our Site and highlight areas which can be improved such as navigation, shopping experience and marketing campaigns. The data stored by these cookies never shows personal details from which your individual identity can be established. 

**Functionality Cookies**   
These cookies remember choices you make such as the country you visit our Site from, language and search parameters such as size, colour or product line. These can then be used to provide you with an experience more appropriate to your selections and to make the visits more tailored and pleasant. The information these cookies collect may be anonymised and they cannot track your browsing activity on other websites. 

**Targeting cookies or advertising cookies**   
These cookies collect information about your browsing habits in order to make advertising more relevant to you and your interests. They are also used to limit the number of times you see an advert as well as help measure the effectiveness of an advertising campaign. The cookies are usually placed by third party advertising networks. They remember the websites you visit and that information is shared with other parties such as advertisers. For example, we use third party companies such as Crazy Egg to provide you with more personalised adverts when visiting other websites.

**Social Media Cookies**   
These cookies allow you to share what you’ve been doing on the Site on social media such as Facebook and Twitter. These cookies are not within our control. Please refer to the respective privacy policies for how their cookies work.   
If you want to delete any cookies that are already on your computer, please refer to the help and support area on your internet browser for instructions on how to locate the file or directory that stores cookies.   
Information on deleting or controlling cookies is available at [www.AboutCookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/). Please note that by deleting our cookies or disabling future cookies you may not be able to access certain areas or features of our Site.   
To find out more about cookies please visit: [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) or see [www.youronlinechoices.eu ](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) which contains further information about behavioural advertising and online privacy. 

## Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)

We employ or our third party tracking utility partner employs a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our Site by informing us what content is effective and allowing us to count users who have visited certain of our pages. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the full stop at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers’ information. 

## Do We Share the Information We Receive?

Your personal information is extremely important to us and our business is not about selling or sharing your information or giving it away to third parties, without your prior consent. The personal information we collect from you is intended to improve our customer service. We may disclose your personal information to our third party suppliers such as companies and individuals who help to fulfil orders, send emails out on our behalf, deliver products, perform data analysis, offer guidance to our marketing department, provide customer service, fulfil shipping requests, and process credit card payments.

By making a purchase and sharing your email address you will be entered on to our customer mailing list to receive product alerts, promotional material as well as our newsletter (unless otherwise indicated). We promise to always make these emails as interesting and relevant to you as we can but if you do not wish to receive promotional material, products alerts or our newsletter you may ask to be removed from our mailing list at any time by following the unsubscribe link located at the bottom of each communication. Alternatively you can email us at [privacy@blucigs.co.uk](mailto:privacy@blucigs.co.uk) and request to be removed from our lists or access your email preferences via the account area and choose what, if anything, you would like to receive.

With your consent you will receive notice if and when information about you might be sent to third parties and you will have the opportunity to agree or refuse to agree to the sharing of your information at that time.

We may disclose your information as required by law, such as to comply with a witness summons, or similar legal process, when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, reduce credit risk or respond to a government request.

If we are involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, we may disclose your personal information to the prospective buyer of such assets and you will be notified via email and/or prominent notice on our Site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your information.   
We may also disclose your personal information to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006. 

## How Secure is the Information You Hold About Me?

Our work is to ensure the protection of your information while it's being transmitted and to continue to provide a secure website and database. We maintain procedural safeguards to protect your information that is collected, stored and disclosed. It is extremely important for you to protect your user login and password from unauthorised access on the computer you use to access your blu account. Make sure to completely sign off your account when using a shared computer. blu cannot be held liable for any types of tampering, database errors or fraud.

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card number) on our order forms or Tax ID, SSN, VAT or your PayPal account information on our affiliate sign up forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

## Are Children Allowed to Use blu?

Absolutely not! blu™ has a strict policy of selling its products to adults aged 18 years and older. If blu believes there is personal information in our hands from a person under the age of 18 years that has breached our policy, all the account information relating to this person will be deleted immediately.

##  Where We Store Your Information 

We may transfer, and store, some of your personal information to countries outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff and suppliers may be engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. Some of these countries may not have equivalent data protection legislation regarding the use and protection of your personal information. By submitting your information to this Site, you consent to such transfers taking place. 

## Access to Your Information

You are entitled to see the information held about you. If you wish to do this, please contact us at [privacy@blucigs.co.uk](mailto:privacy@blucigs.co.uk). We may require you to provide verification of your identity and to pay an administration fee (which is currently £10) to provide a copy of the information we hold. Please note that in certain circumstances we may withhold access to your information where we have the right to do so under current data protection legislation. 

If your information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, amend, delete inaccuracies, or update it by making the change within your account on our Site or by emailing us at any time at [privacy@blucigs.co.uk](mailto:privacy@blucigs.co.uk). 

To request removal of your information from our blog, community forum, or customer testimonials contact us at [privacy@blucigs.co.uk](mailto:privacy@blucigs.co.uk). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.   
We will retain your information for as long as your account is active. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your personal information to provide you services contact us at the email address listed above. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

## Links to Other Sites

This Site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by us. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites.

We encourage you to be aware when you leave our Site and to read the privacy policies of each and every website that collects information.

This privacy policy applies only to information collected by this Site.

## Privacy Policy Notices and Revisions

We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our personal information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to:

Or at:

blu  
PO Box 24043  
Edinburgh, UK  
EH3 1ED
